bookbrowse.com 2019-06-27

# BookBrowse.com's privacy statement

#### Purpose and Data Minimization

BookBrowse is an online magazine for booklovers - including reviews, previews, "beyond the book" articles, author interviews, and reading guides. We collect and use your personal information with your approval, and within the framework of the European Union General Data Protection Regulation (EU GDPR) and the legislation of the United Kingdom related to data protection.

#### Personal Information

BookBrowse.com does not collect any personal information about you, unless you explicitly provide it. 

In the case of members, we store basic contact information required to provide the services you have requested. 

If you subscribe to one of our free newsletters, we use a third-party email host for mailings, so your name and email address are not stored on BookBrowse at all but instead are securely stored at our email host, Constant Contact. You can unsubscribe to any of our emails, or manage your subscriptions, by going to our subscriptions page. 

Email addresses collected when people enter BookBrowse giveaways, quizzes or take part in surveys are used only to select the winning names unless explicitly stated otherwise (for example, if a giveaway offers the opportunity to receive information from a publisher, the email address and first name of those who choose to opt-in will be provided to the publisher.) 

If you win a book in a giveaway, or are a member and request a book to read for either our First Impressions or Book Club program, we will give your name and mailing address to the publisher as part of the mailing list for the book but always with explicit instructions that the list is to be used only to mail the specific book to the specific people listed, and is not to be stored for future use. From time to time the books being mailed may be e-books, in which case we would provide your first name and email address to the publisher, with the same explicit instruction that the list is only to be used for the one-time mailing. 

_**We have never and will never sell, give-away or rent our mailing list**_. 

The only time we would ever knowingly share your information would be with your express permission, or if ordered by a court of law.

#### Financial Information

We make every effort to protect BookBrowse from malicious attack, and comply with industry best practices and standards such as Payment Card Industry (PCI) Security Standards.

**We do not store any credit card information** on BookBrowse - it is passed directly to our payment processor, Paypal.

For common questions about internet security, and some of BookBrowse's specific security, please click here . 

#### Cookies

BookBrowse (like the majority of websites) uses "cookies". When you visit us, BookBrowse's server sends a tiny file (cookie) to your computer containing a sequence of letters and numbers. This is stored on your computer in a special folder for cookies. 

If you visit BookBrowse again, your computer will check its files to see if a cookie matches, and if so it will send this little file back to BookBrowse, so that you are recognized as a returning visitor. This helps us calculate how many people visit in total and when they visit, but we _do not_ collect personal information about you at all. We also _do not_ track or record your visits to other websites, or any other Internet activity not related to BookBrowse. 

This is what the contents of a typical BookBrowse cookie file looks like:   
CFID 212442 bookbrowse.com/1536 3546759168 29693834 

The cookies used by BookBrowse fall into the following categories: 

**1) Website Operation**  
Information essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features, such as (in the case of members) accessing secure areas of the website. Without these cookies, services you have asked for, such as managing your account information, cannot be provided. You cannot opt out of these cookies. 

**Strictly Necessary:** These are essential for the operation of the website. 

Cookie Name | Originating Company | Purpose  
---|---|---  
cfid  
cftoken | BookBrowse | Website Operation  
  
**User Selected:** These are applied if the you interact with the website. 

Cookie Name | Originating Company | Purpose  
---|---|---  
bpop | BookBrowse | Records if you have been offered to subscribe to our newsletter  
ck_priv | BookBrowse | Manages display of privacy alert.  
  
**2) Performance**  
We collect information about how visitors use BookBrowse, for instance which pages visitors go to most often. These cookies don't collect information that identifies a visitor individually; all information is aggregated and therefore anonymous; it is only used to improve how BookBrowse works.

BookBrowse uses the following third-party cookies to track website useage and performance.

Cookie Name | Originating Company | Purpose | Opting Out  
---|---|---|---  
_ga  
_gid  
_gat | Google | These cookies allow us to count user visits and traffic sources so that we can measure and improve the site performance using Google Analytic services. | [Click here to opt-out of Google Analytics](https://tools.google.com/dlpage/gaoptout/index.html)  
__atuvc  
_atuvs | AddThis | This cookie allows you to share information with Social networking sites. | [Click here to opt-out of AddThis cookies](http://www.addthis.com/privacy/opt-out)  

#### Data Protection Declaration for the Use of Google Analytics as a Web Analysis Tool

This website uses Google Analytics, a web analysis service of Google Inc. ("Google", 1600 Amphitheatre Parkway Mountain View, CA 94043, USA). The information about your visit produced by cookies are transmitted to a Google Server in the United States and stored there. In case of IP-anonymisation on our website, your IP address is shorted by Google within EU members States or other contracting States of the European Economic Area prior to transmission.

In exceptional cases, the full IP address is transmitted to a Google Server in the US and shorted there. Google will use this information to assess your use of the website, compile reports on website activities and render other services connected to website and internet use. The IP address transmitted by your browser within the service of google Analytics will not be connected to other Google data. 

#### Advertising

Occasionally publishers running ads on BookBrowse use third-party advertising companies to serve their ads. If you click on these ads, the advertiser may then use cookies to track your visits to their and other websites in order to provide ads that may be of interest to you. If you would like more information about this practice, or you would like to opt out from having your data collected by some advertising networks, visit the DAA opt-out program (currently available at <http://www.aboutads.info/choices/>) or the NAI opt out program (currently available at <http://www.networkadvertising.org/choices/>). 

European visitors may wish to visit the EDAA opt-out program (currently available at <http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/>). 

#### Tell-A-Friend

Visitors sometimes wish to tell a friend about a particular page at BookBrowse, or send themselves a reminder. For this reason, like many other websites, BookBrowse provides a convenient 'tell-a-friend' tool that allows you to send a personal message to a friend telling them about BookBrowse. 

Email addresses are used only to send this one-time message, and are not stored or recorded by BookBrowse in any way. 

#### "My Reading List"

Members have the option of creating and storing book lists on BookBrowse - for example to keep track of books read and to read. Members can also record their personal thoughts on these books. At this time, member reading lists can only be viewed by the individual member when that member is logged in. They are not available to the general public to view at all. Some members have requested that BookBrowse provide the ability for lists to be made public - either so that the member can provide access to specific people or so that their lists are freely available to all internet users. At the moment BookBrowse does not allow this, but if we were to in the future, the default setting would be that a list remains private unless an individual member specifically opts to make his or her list(s) public.

#### Information Provided by Third Parties

_Third Party Content_   
BookBrowse contains a considerable amount of information provided by third parties, including, but not limited to, advertising, excerpts, reviews, interviews, book summaries and text links. As such, content at BookBrowse.com does not necessarily represent the views of the owners of BookBrowse LLC and is not endorsed by us. 

_Third Party Links_   
This site contains links to other sites, including but not limited to, banner advertising and text links. BookBrowse LLC is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of any third party sites, and a link to a third party site should not be seen as an endorsement by BookBrowse of that site. 

The "Buy This Book" links contain affiliate information, which means BookBrowse may receive a small commission if you purchase the book using these links.

#### Security

While no online service is 100% secure, we work very hard to protect information about you against unauthorised access, use, alteration, or destruction, and take reasonable measures to do so.

As has been described, we do not store credit card information at BookBrowse. Your passwords are encoded, and not readable by us. The entire website is secured using HTTPS, meaning all communications between your browser and the website are encrypted. And finally, we comply with the Credit Card Industry PCI guidelines, which provides a long list of security requirement to minimise the risk of unauthrixed data access.

#### Your Rights

Under the EU GDPR and at any time, you have the right to address the controller or our data processing officer and request information on how your data is stored and used. You also have a right to rectification of your data. Or you can have the processing restricted, meaning a right to have processing limited to parts of your data. At any time, you may object to the processing of your personal data. When you do so, we will check whether there are any conflicting legal transmitting and processing obligations and inform you accordingly. You also have a right to data portability, meaning that we hand over your data in a structured, commonly used and machine-readable format determined by us upon your request.

In addition, if you feel that we do not treat your personal data properly and as laid out in this Policy, you have a right to complain to the supervisory authority responsible for your country. 

When you've given your consent to the processing of your data you may, of course, revoke your consent at any time.

If you receive emails from us, you also have a right to object at any time so that we stop sending you emails. 

**Name of the controller:**  
BookBrowse LLC (Limited Liability Company)

**Chief Executive Officer:**  
Davina Morgan-Witts  
BookBrowse LLC  
19630 Allendale Ave, #2157  
Saratoga, CA, 95070  
E-Mail: info@bookbrowse.com

**Data Protection Officer:**  
Paul Morgan-Witts  
BookBrowse LLC  
19630 Allendale Ave, #2157  
Saratoga, CA, 95070  
E-Mail: info@bookbrowse.com

#### Contacting BookBrowse.com

If you have any questions about this privacy statement, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this website, please [contact us](https://www.bookbrowse.com/contactus "contact us"). 

Last updated May 2018
